hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft and
today i've had a pretty awesome idea so
last episode we kind of founded and
established hermitland which is the new
minigame district that i'm hoping that
all the other hermits will get involved
in at some point i haven't really done
much i've just like added a bridge over
here but it all needs a lot of
improvement but i don't really want to
act too much until i've got everyone
else kind of involved so what i have
done
is actually flattened this area over
here because what i'm gonna do is add my
very first mini game to this area so
what is my idea well it's actually a
very very simple mini game however
it's one of those ones that's very small
and simple but it takes an awful long
time
to produce my mini game is going to be
called dig straight down
and it's going to be exactly what you
think you have to dig straight down so
what i'm going to do is just define
where this area is going to be these are
going to be the blocks that you can dig
straight down in and this will make
sense in a little while there we go so
these are all the options now as we know
in minecraft digging straight down is a
really really bad idea
so we're going to capitalize on the risk
of this by creating a mini game that's
entirely dedicated to digging straight
down what we're going to do is offer up
the chance to win more diamonds than you
pay
so what you would do is you come over
here to where my mini game is and you
pay your five diamonds you then take off
all your gear and put it in a locker
then you get given a fancy pickaxe and
that's pretty much it you then take your
pickaxe and you mine down and you have
to dig straight down you will come
across all kinds of
wars and blocks that are your reward but
at any point you could hit lava now
obviously what i'm going to do is i'm
going to pre-determine where all of
these blocks and the lava is so you can
chicken out at any point but if you go
too far you will hit lava obviously what
i need to do now is set all of these up
all the way up to the top on each one of
these so i'm going to quickly have to
dig out all of this and it's going to
take me an awful long time to do the
other thing that i need to do is
actually get a load of diamond ore as
the reward for this mini game
so let's start digging straight down
shall we i thought that this wasn't
going to take very long but
unfortunately in the 1.14.4
update it reintroduced an old bug called
phantom blocks and it meant that every
now and again just an invisible block
would stop me from walking or
it just meant i had to fly away then fly
back and it just wasted a lot of my time
but eventually i got all the way to the
bottom and i mined it all out it just
took a long time
digging all the way to bedrock took a
surprisingly long time
now i don't know if i've done a very
good job of
excuse me
oh
man there's some serious pillager
problems going on let's just take care
of these really quick otherwise they're
going to be super annoying yep they're
taken care of so what i actually need is
lots of diamond ore and then i need lots
of other things that you can potentially
get and then i also need lots of lava as
well
so what we're going to do is now collect
lots of materials from underground in a
big mining session yep gotta go back to
mining to get all of the ores that i
need to make this game work and i've got
to be very careful about the maths
otherwise
i could end up losing more diamonds than
i make
so this is a really really sped-up
version of just part of a clip of the
amount of mining that i had to do and i
got quite a lot of ores from it not a
problem but what i'm worried about is
this mini game probably will not make a
profit however i'm still going to make
it because it's going to be a lot of fun
basically i have to contribute you know
between zero and nine diamond ores to
each one of the 16 options
meaning on average it's going to be
three diamond ores
meaning that if i just mined those
diamonds it probably would give me
more diamonds than i'm charging people
to play the game however this isn't
about making money this is just about
making a cool mini game for people to
play and we'll see how it all pans out
so i've managed to collect a lot of
stuff i won't even need to use all of
this but look at this i've got loads of
lapis i've got loads of coal blocks and
i've got a stack and over a stack and a
half of diamond ore
now it's going to cost five diamonds to
select one and there are 16 of these
and i'm going to guarantee that at least
one diamond ore is in each one but some
of them might have as many as seven so
it's a real risk reward game however
remember
as you dig down you might find this many
diamond doors but if you don't chicken
out at the right time you could end up
hitting lava so what i'm going to do is
set up just one of these so that you can
experience how this looks so i'm going
to use a silk i'm going to use a silk
touch just so this makes sense you dig
straight down and you see what you get
at some point you're going to start
coming across
some other blocks such as ah diamond now
as you get closer to the bottom the more
chance that there is that you're going
to go straight into lava
and if you get to that point
you've lost because you're going to die
so the idea is you dig down you take
what you can
and when you think that you've pushed it
far enough
then you bail at the last second and
they will have a bunch of scaffolding so
that they can get out so now i've got to
spend a long time
sorting out
what's going to go where and all of the
lava is going to be at a different level
but if you want diamonds you've got to
dig as low as possible all of the lava
blocks will be kind of near the bottom
but the diamond blocks will indicate
that you're getting close
all right so it's time to start divvying
up what diamonds are going where this
took literally three
or four hours
i cannot exaggerate enough how much time
i've spent on this but it is done and
all we've got to do now
is figure out how we're going to detail
this and decorate this because this is a
theme park basically we do need to make
sure that this looks really quite nice
for our customers to come and try out
the game so we're going to do a little
time lapse to decorate this place and
then we'll get scar to come and try it
out so to decorate this i wanted it to
be
in the same style as like frontierland
or like you know the old west style so i
added a bunch of barrels around i also
added like a gravelly theme around it
kind of like it's a quarry so that's why
there's like rocks around it but
obviously i still want that area in the
middle to show all of the 16 options for
digging straight down
then all i had to do was decorate it a
little bit more because the feel of it
is important i could have just left that
game with 16 blocks open on the ground
and just a chest but that wouldn't be
very mini game or theme park like so i
have to add these extra decorations to
make it really feel like a cool mini
game so i decided to add a crane very
similar to the one that was on my build
off house and that's just going to have
some barrels on a pole or
something it's really just for
decoration purposes but it it added
quite a lot to the build and because
this is a mini game in a theme park i
then decided to add a proper sign for it
dsd which obviously stands for dig
straight down and that
is the decoration for my mini game and i
think it came out rather well
and we are finished we just need to add
a couple of lights here and it is done
so what i've got here is a really cool
looking decoration for my new game
dig straight down or dsd for short i'm
pretty proud of how this has all come
out especially as the main part of the
game is just this and then everything
else around it is for decoration because
this is meant to be a proper minigame
hub between andersite and lava there are
zero to nine diamond doors so there's a
chance of getting absolutely zero
diamonds and there's a chance of getting
nine diamonds and by diamonds i mean
diamond ore so there's an extra when i
get all of these pickaxes sorted which
is my last item on the list of things i
need to do
then you may even get times three
because i'm going to enchant all of
these with looting
so let's crack on and get these pickaxes
sorted
i did say that this was a very simple
game but it's just taking so so long to
sort out but i absolutely knew that when
i started this project okay i've got
myself a shulker box full of
some iron pickaxes with looting three on
them and that should be exactly what we
need so hopefully we can now meet up
with scar
to check out this game together so he
can be my first ever test dummy to make
sure that this works and hopefully we
can make five diamonds at the same time
there we go adding all the pickaxes now
the reason that i've chosen iron is
because i want this to be slow
and i want them to be kind of panicking
so the rate at which you mine with an
iron pickaxe is a lot slower than a
diamond and there's no haste too so it's
gonna be it's gonna be really slow to
get down there and the tension should
rise quite quickly so we've got our own
pickaxes we got our dirt
and i think that's about it so hopefully
i could just tell scar that it's open
now and he can come and give it a go god
dsd is open if you want to come and try
it out i'm fairly sure that scar is
going to end up in lava scar i know
you've been watching me build this so
do you want to be the the first one to
try it out do you want to check this
check out my new mini game
i brought my wallet because i'm ready to
play i know you like theme parks
that's true very true do you even know
what this game is
no i have no idea but i saw you from
afar and it was very intriguing okay so
this game is called dig straight down
and it's pretty much what it says on the
tin i've got my instructions for you
right here i'm actually going to ask you
to read them because if you don't
understand them i've messed up
so if you if you could read them and see
if it all makes sense
then we'll know if i've done this
correctly
wow okay
all right i'm just going to brush off
that shade okay
welcome okay that distracted me
that just threw me off welcome to dig
straight down one put all of your stuff
in the lockers all items are at risk
scary take a pic and two stacks of dirt
all right pay five oh five diamonds
that's expensive i'm trying to get up to
seven
diamond block stacks so that's gonna
hurt but you could make diamonds from
this game you can make diamonds
oh really okay i will read on pay five
diamonds and choose an end as i block
dig straight down there is a hundred
percent chance of wait there's a hundred
percent 100 chance 100 chance of lava
every single one will 100 have lava
but i would die in the hot stuff
yeah yeah you will
okay
five
fail using dirt when your nerves get to
you oh he's in he's easy
i hope this is fun i haven't seen it yet
my wallet's a little heavy it's kind of
hard on my back oh my goodness
oh
man i'm ready to go you pick up a
pickaxe you pick up some dirt in case
you want to bail now remember you you
have to bail at some point otherwise you
will end up in lava
all right so choose wisely there's an
andesite block
and uh i think i remember where some of
the good ones are
okay okay you mean you know just cool
hot you know there's there's also more
than just diamonds there's there's some
other loot as well but the the diamonds
are the ones you're really after so
choose one
hot cold good bad i'm not saying
anything
huh over here over here
okay nothing over here
i'm not saying anything okay that was
synthetic i'll be honest i honestly
don't really remember
okay all right down you go
okay oh oh oh redstone perfect oh fancy
redwater blogs
oh this is good i like it
but you have to remember there's lava at
some point in the game
dude what is this block right here it's
like it's cold it's cold it doesn't look
like coal
it's cold oh it is cold it didn't look
like oh oh okay okay
quinn
the cold block is the scariest thing
i've ever seen in my life
keep going
i thought it was all over
keep going okay i think i i really want
a diamond i'm gonna go till i get
diamonds i'm doing it
oh i just feel like it's gonna be all
over any minute
is this is it is the tension building
dude i'm wiping my hand off it was
getting a little sweaty
i'm shaking over here
remember you can you can bail at any
time remember dude i'm determined to get
a diamond i oh emeralds two oh this is
amazing look at this
it goes down really really deep so oh no
no
no no no no no
he lost it all right
so
oh no
and i totally knew before you went in
that you picked the one that has zero
diamonds in you picked
the only one in the entire game with
zero diamonds
dude i was determined you know i'm
trying to get that full stack of diamond
blocks
oh you left your wallet here i'm out all
right see you later scar
no nice knowing ya
get back just joking scar come back come
back
oh that was a long hike back i made it
um yeah for your convenience i've just
put a bed here so that you can uh
respawn here if you uh if you die
you just wanted me to work on my legs
today
i would like to play again okay sweet
okay let's do one more so you've
actually eliminated the one with zero
diamonds so you now know that you can
dig down
and get at least one diamond right
yes also that was cruel giving me one
that didn't have a diamond
i didn't give it to you you chose it and
i knew it i knew he went in there i
smirked i didn't smirk
remember i was like this i was like hot
cold and you're like and i'm like oh
this must be the good one i'm ready and
i'm going i'm going right now i'm going
straight in you want to pay first
oh
sorry
and do you want to sleep as well i will
wait for the sun to settle in the east
west
tick tock
oh wait it still has a ways to go
all right you ready ska to choose
another one
i'm well rested and ready to go i'm
going to this one right here what do you
think
i don't remember how i don't remember
how many that has i only remember the
one that had zero because i remember how
how much i was like oh you mean the one
i was in okay all right i remember which
one has the most and which one has the
least so i can tell you that that one
doesn't have the most but i'm not going
to tell you which one it is so you might
as well go for it
okay
all right he's going for it
good luck ska
all right we're going deep here
going deep deep deep oh
oh i want to get my money back
five okay i paid for one game
okay that was scary all right
this is good this is good
at any point
no no i'm gonna i'm gonna get i'm gonna
pay myself back any point that could be
lava remember that you can stop you stop
trying to jinx me up there
any time no i'm going deep man you might
want to check your eye level as well
yes
i am cutting my losses
[Music]
he's made his money back and he's
bailing he's out well actually i lost
one diamond but i'm okay with that well
that was worth a diamond well done
that was a smart move i just got some
redstone i think there was one more
diamond down there but you you made the
right you made the right decision you
made the right decision ah look at this
look at these diamonds look at them all
right sweet well i'm glad you like the
game i'm hoping other people are gonna
play and uh i hope that they are smart
like you and leave as soon as they get
more than five diamonds
this was awesome gg goodbye
it did not take long
from when i told the other hermits that
my game was live for them to come and
try it out for themselves so i was still
hanging around and i got to see it so x
actually chose the one that had nine
diamonds in it
but he decided to bail when he got five
diamond ores which was really smart so
there was still four in there and i can
use that for the next round so
yeah i definitely lost diamonds on that
particular one but i'll gain them in
other places remember every time someone
does the dig straight down game they
will probably just leave straight after
they get five diamonds or they'll keep
going until they end up in lafa like our
good old friend cub fan did he decided
to go down down and down and he
committed and then yeah
didn't end well for him so it's kind of
fun watching them play this game
it's been overnight since i made the
mini game and wow
look at this
so many diamonds 45 diamonds that is
pretty good that is really really good
so there are eight spaces left meaning
half of it has been played i might need
to refill this before the game's even
gone live on youtube this is ridiculous
well i'm gonna leave it like that for
now i have no idea how many people have
died on this or how many people made it
but i'm sure there's still some diamond
ore underneath there because some people
will of course bail before they get all
of them so let's leave dig straight down
for now it's a really cool mini game and
i hope to come up with a few more mini
games like that but i'll be honest
that game took all day to make literally
all day so i haven't got time for much
else oh
no no no no no no no no no
that's a someone needs to cover this up
but let's go back to the old lands
because
iskall told me on discord that
he has completely upgraded sahara so
i've got to check this out so when he
said upgrade zahara he meant he tore all
of this out and completely remade it so
that it works flawlessly apparently but
i think everything kind of works the
same from a user experience so let's
order something shall we i'll order an
iron block shall we
order received i wonder if it uses a
minecart it still uses a minecart system
we were going to change this to ice so
it would be much much quicker
but i think that's for a future update
so the order has arrived at the
warehouse waiting for customer to
confirm order maybe soon it's still
quite slow
oh there we go okay i've got some nice
feedback on that and then
it should be on its way and i think we
can actually go and see it because like
i said this should come out there it is
there's the order
yeah so you can imagine that this would
be a lot faster
if the item was on ice because it would
just go
so it takes too long to get from the
warehouse all the way to the shop front
that's for sure so we'll change that to
ice when we can
and then grab your goods and oh arriving
there we go block of iron
done brilliant and then collect receipt
so one diamond to be paid
look at that
look at that a payment received there we
go so we got 32 iron blocks and it
didn't mess up so sahara works
and that means that sahara is officially
out of bait oh look he's even he's even
removed the beta sign so yeah sahara is
officially open and working but they're
still
still so many improvements that need to
be made so one of the things that we
definitely need to do is create some
sort of entertainment system in here for
people waiting for their order they need
to be able to entertain themselves so
that might fall onto me to do we
definitely need to promote sahara some
more to get people shopping here
frequently
and of course we need to change that to
ice so that the mine car isn't so slow
but all of that will be over time
because sahara is a long-term project
and we need to make sure that it
continues to make diamonds
so let's have a look in the vault
actually because we've got a vault where
we keep all of our sahara diamonds
and
oh the money pile is growing very very
slowly so that's exciting
but there is one more thing that i
really need to do and i need to get my
diamonds back because i lost them and
i've got lots of diamond or now so it's
not really bad but i did lose quite a
lot of diamonds
and it's great and all that i had to you
know mine for three hours but it would
be really great if i could just find all
of my diamonds again but i'm gonna need
to keep a lot of these diamond ores for
my mini game so
yeah i've got to be careful so i'm sure
i can figure out a way to get my
diamonds back so what i want to do
is create another base
not here in my giant pillar of a base
because i need it to be secret it needs
to be hidden it needs to be underground
i need to create
greens
greens lab greens
laboratory i need a secret lab where i'm
going to work on some major major
projects so i think i might leave this
area
all together and make my secret area but
actually it's not very secret if i tell
you where it is we'll sort that out next
episode because i'm afraid that's all we
have time for today
but this is very exciting
this is so weird how it like vibrates
[Music]
anyway thank you very much for watching
everyone we will build a secret
laboratory
next episode so that we can try and
figure out a way to get our diamonds
back thank you very much for watching
and good
bye